English-language manuscript verse in the Houghton Library, circa 1000-1820: First-line index.
English-language manuscript verse in the Houghton Library circa 1000-1820,
How oft, exulting from these banks, I've come (incomplete) MS Eng 611, i, 92v
How oft has my imagination brought (incomplete) MS Eng 612, iii, 101v
How oft the unwary birds have met MS Eng 680, 49
How oft through this responsive grove MS Eng 1038.1, 15
How pleasing is beauty, how sweet are the charms MS Eng 895, 24
How pleasing is the pain a lover feels (incomplete) MS Eng 611, iii, 8
How rich the wave, in front, imprest MS Keats 2.12, 1v
How sacred and how innocent MS Eng 611, i, 83v
How sad our state by nature is MS Eng 614, 93v; MS Eng 614, 132
How sad's my state, I know not how MS Eng 614, 48v
How shall bonny Ann lie MS Eng 1491 (4), ii, 75v
How shall I praiseI merit none. If thou hast kindness done thee, I have pleasure (incomplete) MS Eng 612, ii, 102v
How shall weak eyes of flesh, weigh'd down MS Eng 614, 118
How short, alas! the longest lives MS Eng 612, ii, 110v
How short and hasty is our life Autograph file, W: Isaac Watts, 11
How silly were our sages heretofore (incomplete) MS Eng 616, i, 65v
How sits this city, late most populous MS Eng 966.3, 99v; MS Eng 966.5, 21v
How smoothly the minutes, dear Celadon, flow MS Eng 895, 48v
How soft is the scene MS Eng 612, ii, 102
How speed the outlaws! stand they well prepared (incomplete) MS Eng 1274, ch. 39
How sweet a quietude's in fetters found (incomplete) MS Eng 611, iii, 13
How sweet a thing is death. To all who know *82-408, 39
How sweet is the woodland with fleet hound and horn MS Eng 1038.1, 16
How sweet the name of Jesus sounds MS Eng 616, ii, 42v
How sweet the plaint of that lone nightingale MS Eng 1316, 4
How sweetly smile the banks of Dee MS Eng 1491 (4), i, 88
How swiftly wasted in a sigh MS Eng 614, 120v
How tall the fir! And yet his root is found MS Eng 611, i, 18
How Tallboy, Kill-Prick, Suck-Prick, did contend MS Eng 636F, 114
How tedious the loitering minutes roll on (incomplete) MS Eng 614, 9
How terrible is passion! how our reason (incomplete) MS Eng 612, iii, 42v
How terribly triumphant comes the wretch (incomplete) MS Eng 612, ii, 98v
How! the first baut person tis not your due MS Eng 633, 74v
How these antique towers (incomplete) MS Eng 265, 7
How this conv-t-n came about MS Eng 895, 98v
How time turns upside down and fortune sails MS Eng 645, 16v
How transporting is the pleasure when two hearts like ours unite MS Eng 1038.1, 40
How treach'rously do all behave MS Eng 614, 46v
How unequally in some are joined (incomplete) MS Eng 1312, 47
How unhappy is he MS Eng 612, iii, 134v
How vain are all the hopes we center here MS Eng 614, 27v
How vain are all things here below Autograph file, W: Isaac Watts, 8v
How vain are mortal man's endeavors MS Eng 768 (vol. 1), 62
How vain are women in their youthful days (incomplete) MS Eng 611, ii, 88
How vain, Sir knight, is thy affected rage MS Eng 629, 82
How vain the wish our back to fix MS Eng 1461, 238
How vain these tears. Is man decreed MS Eng 612, iii, 118
How vain this tribute; vain, this lowly lay (incomplete) MS Eng 776, 6v
How vainly I purpose when from her I part MS Eng 623
How wanton widow MS Eng 1491 (4), i, 189v
How wayward and perverse a thing is woman (incomplete) MS Eng 616, i, 13
How we fare, if you would know MS Eng 645, 51v
How weak, alas, is all the pow'r of man (incomplete) MS Eng 614, 9
How widely spread the interests of our theme (incomplete) *EC8. W8915.838s, p. 413
How wondrous few, by avarice uncontrolled (incomplete) MS Eng 612, iii, 107
How wretched is the state that all are in MS Eng 1278, folder 12-17, no. 15
Howe'er to foreign fashion we submit (incomplete) MS Eng 616, i, 21v
Howl on, ye winds, and beat, ye rains (incomplete) MS Am 2349, v, p. 177
Hubbert, profane of late, is turned precise MS Eng 699, 25
Hugh, 'twas a gross mistake when men did call MS Eng 645, 15
Hum, my love, lovest thou me MS Eng 686, 73v
Human, human, I say take heed MS Eng 1015, 123
Humid seal of soft affections MS Keats 3.13, i, 18v
Humor is now the jest we try things in (incomplete) MS Eng 612, iii, 136
Hunting I reckon very good MS Eng 611, i, 119v
Huntley man and marshall MS Eng 1498, 44v
Hush, hush! tread softly! hush, hush, my dear MS Keats 3.2, 131; MS Keats 3.6, p. 28; MS Keats 2.20
Hush! tread softly, Our little Enoch sleeps upon you bed MS Eng 630, 10
Huzza to King William and his delicate mate MS Mus 237, ii, 90v
Hyde, though in agonies, her graces keeps MS Eng 768 (vol. 1), 38
Hynde Horn's bound, love, and Hynde Horn's free MS Eng 1471, vii, 60
Hyppolacus' illustrious son replies (incomplete) MS Eng 631, 13v
I
I absolve my lord Yes, I absolve you from your vows and faith (incomplete) MS Eng 611, i, 10v
I, alas, Have lived but on this earth a few sad years (incomplete) MS Eng 1274, ch. 13
I always seize the topic of the day Autograph file, H: Theodore E. Hook, 1
I always take my judgment from a fool MS Eng 1167, 21; MS Eng 889, 14
I am a balsam wonderful MS Eng 1488, 43
I am a blade of the mumping trade MS Eng 1503 (3), vol. ii, p. 130
I am a guilty, miserable wretch (incomplete) MS Eng 1274, ch. 45
I am a laboring man, And we seldom have leisure to run mad (incomplete) MS Eng 265.6, v. 2 (twice)
I am a little world made cunningly MS Eng 966.5, 18v; MS Eng 966.4, 83v
I am a mere combustible fire MS Eng 1488, 42
I am a poor shepherd, yet born of high blood MS Eng 1503 (3), vol. iii, p. 35
I am a prince, and meet you without odds (incomplete) MS Eng 611, iii, 30
I am a saucy scribbler MS Eng 629, 121
I am a young dairy maid, both braw and light MS Eng 1491 (3), 62v
I am a young woman that married lately MS Am 2349, iii, p. 37
I am an old prophet and newly come over MS Eng 895, 9
I am an unfortunate lover MS Eng 629, 115v
I am Armand the great, did you ever hear of me MS Eng 1471, v, 144v
I am as brown as brown can be MS Am 2349, xxix, 1072
I am as sober as your reverence (incomplete) MS Eng 612, ii, 43
I am but a little child *82-408, 26
I am but one who do the world despise (incomplete) MS Eng 265.6, v. 2 (twice)
I am called arsenic sure MS Eng 1488, 42v
I am called by the name of a Venus-star MS Eng 1488, 48
I am content, nay pleased with my loss MS Eng 686, 80
I am free from men of pleasure's cares (incomplete) MS Keats 1.39, 3
I am gone from the world. You may perceive indeed MS Eng 1015, 111
I am in truth a country youth unused to London fashions MS Eng 1038.1, 39
I am intending for to write MS Eng 1491 (4), i, 154v
I am monarch alone of my shelves MS Eng 692, 45
I am monarch of all I survey (incomplete) MS Eng 569.65, 16v; MS Eng 692, 45
I am never aloneat early dawn MS Eng 630, 39v
I am no Homer's hero, you all know MS Eng 1167, 16; MS Eng 889, 9
I am no statesman But being set on such a wedding night (incomplete) MS Eng 265.6, v. 2
I am not grieved, my dearest wife MS Eng 692, 37
I am not Of that soft temper, that the eye of beauty (incomplete) MS Eng 612, iii, 8v
I am not what I was, but just the reverse MS Eng 1323, 48
I am now fifteen years of age MS Eng 1471, v, 67v
I am of service to a sow MS Eng 569.67, 80
I am Ormand the brave, did you never hear of me (incomplete) MS Eng 1470, 33
I am pretty and useful in various ways MS Eng 1323, 11
I am resolv'd, I will not stop his journey (incomplete) MS Eng 612, ii, 104
I am Sir Oracle And when I ope my lips let no dog bark (incomplete) MS Eng 692, 35
I am still Old Cleon, fat and unwieldy; I shall never (incomplete) MS Eng 612, iii, 33
I am that champion great of power MS Eng 1503 (3), vol. ii, p. 158
I am the Duke of Athole's nurse MS Eng 1471, vii, 87
I am the king, the prince of drunkards MS Eng 512, 17
I am the man whose eyes have seen MS Eng 611, iii, 35v
I am Tityrus Orpheus MS Am 505, 75
I am two fools, I know MS Eng 966.3, 25v; MS Eng 966.1, 37v; MS Eng 966.7, 2; MS Eng 966.5, 130; MS Eng 966.4, 205
I am unable, yonder beggar cries MS Eng 966.3, 74v; MS Eng 966.5, 172; MS Keats 3.13, i, 5
I arise from dreams of thee *EC8. Sh445. 929n, 20; Mus 604.2.701F, 1
I asked a thief to steal me a peach MS Eng 1167, 58; MS Eng 1167, 76; MS Eng 889, 48
I asked my dear friend, Orator Prig MS Eng 1167, 31; MS Eng 889, 24
I at Praeneste whilst you plead at Rome (incomplete) MS Eng 631, 6
I bathe in rose dew and ne'er fail MS Eng 768 (vol. 1), 22
I beg you bide at hame, Margaret MS Eng 1444, 12v; MS Eng 1444, 40
I bless the Lord, because I grow MS Eng 631, 34v
I bought a cock an' he pleased me well MS Eng 1491 (4), i, 150
I bow'd my neck indeed to mighty love (incomplete) MS Eng 611, iii, 24v
I, Britain's kind Egeria, will protect (incomplete) MS Eng 731, folder 275, 3v
I burn, and cruel you in vain MS Eng 626, 10v
I C U R brave Monsieur Carr MS Eng 628, 165
I call myself vegetable MS Eng 1488, 43v
I came from England into France MS Eng 626, 71v
I can conduct you, lady, to a low (incomplete) MS Eng 611, i, 132v
I can love both fair and brown MS Eng 966.3, 66v; MS Eng 966.7, 53; MS Eng 966.5, 151; MS Eng 966.4, 207v
I can no longer hold, my body grows MS Eng 626, 66
I can wear a horn, and blow it not (incomplete) MS Eng 265.6, v. 2 (twice)
I cannot bend the bow wherein to shoot I sue MS Eng 686, 32
I cannot brook your gadding; you're a fair one (incomplete) MS Eng 612, iii, 32v
I cannot either eat or drink MS Am 1177, 12
I cannot go, nor sit, nor stand, the beggar cries MS Eng 966.4, 217
I cannot live and love thee not MS Keats 3.13, i, 6v
I cannot preach nor read but Rainoldes twice MS Eng 699, 30
I cannot stifle this gigantic woe (incomplete) MS Eng 611, ii, 101
I can't put out love's great and sacred fire (incomplete) MS Eng 611, iii, 20v
"I can't say," said the monarch, "that may be" (incomplete) MS Keats 2.29.2; MS Keats 2.29.1
I cative curate languishes MS Eng 1491 (4), ii, 270
I chanced sweet Lesbia's voice to hear MS Eng 626, 46v
I charge ye a', ye ladies fair MS Eng 1470, 91
I choosed my love at the bonny gates of Gight MS Eng 1491 (4), ii, 73
I came from the heaven most high MS Eng 1488, 44
I came, my sweet mistress, your pardon to crave MS Am 1448 (nos. 20-63), no. 40
I came not fondly to upbraid, but show (incomplete) MS Eng 616, i, 72v
I could not choose but gaze; a fascination (incomplete) MS Eng 1274, ch. 23
I count it long since I received MS Eng 614, 47
I cry your mercypitylove!aye, love MS Keats 3.6, p. 58
I did not know the lord, nor do I strive MS Eng 966.7, 98
I did not know thee, Lord, nor do I strive MS Eng 966.3, 45v
I dinna like the Meg-o-mony-feet MS Eng 966.1, 9v
I do believe her steadfastly, and know her (incomplete) MS Eng 265.6, v. 2
I do believe her steadfastly, I know her MS Eng 265.6, v. 2
I do forswear but yet I do return MS Eng 247.5, 68v
I do not doubt, Roxana, but you will (incomplete) MS Eng 611, iii, 22
I do not feel as if I were a man (incomplete) MS Eng 1274, ch. 46
I doubt the task will be as hard MS Eng 612, ii, 39
I down in a meadow one evening did tarry MS Eng 512, 84v
I drank; I lik'd it not; 'twas rage; 'twas noise (incomplete) MS Eng 616, i, 63v
I dream'd a dreary dream last night MS Eng 1497, i, 10v
I dream'd I lost a pearl, and so it prov'd (incomplete) MS Eng 612, iii, 74v
I dreamed that as I was wandering by the way *EC8. Sh445. 929n, 18
I dreamt a dream! what can it mean MS Eng 1167, 52; MS Eng 889, 45
I dreamt that buried in my fellow clay MS Keats 3.13, ii, 36v
I dreamt that buried in my fellow's clay MS Eng 676F, 20v
I early went with muffled face MS Eng 768 (vol. 2), 35
I' every revolution of the state *82-408, 149
I faint with fear, I blush for shame MS Eng 1494, 6
I fear some planet of a fatal aspect (incomplete) MS Eng 612, iii, 42v
I feared the fury of my wind MS Eng 1167, 57
I fell sick and very, very sick MS Eng 1471, i, 60
I find I have lost MS Eng 935, wreath, 85v
I find, says he, she wants a doctor (incomplete) MS Eng 611, ii, 94
I find your passion for me, is but small (incomplete) MS Eng 611, iii, 22
I first was dead; now this glad vantage have MS Eng 228, 20
I fix mine eye on thine, and there MS Eng 966.3, 65; MS Eng 966.1, 23v; MS Eng 966.5, 140v; MS Eng 966.4, 183
I fly all public care and venal strife (incomplete) MS Eng 616, i, 36v
I forbid ye a', ye gay ladies MS Eng 1486 (3), 65
I forbid ye, maidens a' MS Eng 1497, ii, 63
I forbid ye, maidens a' MS Eng 1497, ii, 63
I forbid ye maidens a' that wear goud on your gear MS Am 2349, xxii, 201
I forbid ye maidens a' that wear the goud on your gear MS Eng 1500, 58v
I forbid you a' ye gay ladies MS Eng 1486 (4), 17 and 79
I found it written in old hand MS Eng 1508, 1
I found them blind, I taught them how to see MS Eng 1167, 18; MS Eng 889, 11
I gaed a waefu' gate yestreen Autograph file, B: Robert Burns, 1
I gaed to Newecastle MS Eng 1491 (4), i, 162
I gaed to the market as an honest woman said MS Eng 1471, v, 50v
I gained a boon, my aching head MS Eng 1497, ii, 109v
I give you the end of a golden string MS Eng 1167, 24; MS Eng 1167, 69; MS Eng 889, 17
I go; but first I make this hearty wish (incomplete) MS Eng 612, iii, 6
I grant a virgin's modesty may blush (incomplete) MS Eng 612, iii, 7
I had a Cloris, my delight MS Eng 895, 50v
I had a dove and the sweet dove died MS Keats 3.10 (3); MS Keats 1.45
I had a dove, but the sweet dove died MS Keats 3.2, 187
I had sense in dreams of a beauty rare MS Eng 959, 2
I had three sons a' young stout and bauld MS Eng 1497, i, 93v
I hae a dream baith night an' day MS Eng 601.66, 27v
I hae been at the ware-horse MS Eng 1491 (4), i, 115v
I hae been courting at a lass MS Eng 1491 (4), i, 105v
I hae been east, I hae been west MS Eng 1491 (4), i, 157
I hae courted a lassie a twelvemonth and more MS Eng 1491 (4), ii, 4v; MS Eng 1470, 41
I hae gotten a braw new gown MS Eng 1491 (4), i, 117
I hae laid a herring in saut (incomplete) MS Am 2349, ii, p. 237; MS Eng 1486 (3), 17v
I hae nae kith, I hae nae kin MS Eng 1486 (3), 54
I hate inconstancyI loathe, detest (incomplete) MS Eng 630, 57
I hate the man who builds his name MS Eng 1038.2, 51
I hate the vulgar dietyes MS Eng 645, 32v
I hate those coward tribes MS Eng 1038.1, 5v
I have a love so fair MS Eng 628, 162v
I have a secret comfort here MS Eng 692, 58v
I have a tow'r in Dalesbury MS Eng 1470, 258
I have been in love myself, but never found yet (incomplete) MS Eng 265.6, v. 2
I have chosen Wednesday, at which I first was born MS Eng 1488, 49
I have done one braver thing MS Eng 966.3, 72v; MS Eng 966.7, 37; MS Eng 966.5, 153v; MS Eng 966.4, 201
I have examined and defined MS Keats 3.3, p. 47
I have no humor to adore the face MS Eng 626, 63v
I have no vein in verse, but if I could MS Eng 686, 70
I have sinned against the Lord MS Eng 611, iii, 35
I hear this towm does so abound MS Eng 602F, 55; MS Eng 623; MS Eng 636F, 6v
I heard a cow low, a bonny cow low MS Eng 1498, 14
I heard a judge his tipstaff call MS Eng 692, 27
I heard an angel singing MS Eng 1167, 58; MS Eng 1167, 69; MS Eng 889, 48
I heard the rack As earth and sky would mingle; but myself (incomplete) MS Eng 731, folder 142
I herde a carping of a clerk MS Am 2349, xxiv, 477
I here stand keeper while 'tis light MS Eng 686, 61v
I hold as faith MS Eng 768 (vol. 1), 78v
I hold my weary soul in my teeth (incomplete) MS Eng 611, iii, 7
I hold Osorio dear; he is your son MS Eng 947.9, 3
I hope and so do you: but here it lies MS Eng 1085, recto of final leaf
I hope you are contented, gentlemen MS Eng 674, 16v
I in these flow'ry meads would be MS Eng 1490, 80
I knew him for a rogueish boy (incomplete) MS Eng 265.6, v. 2
I knew him in Padua, a fantastical scholar (incomplete) MS Eng 611, iii, 5v
I knew they would perish MS Am 988, 22v
I knew what I did when I first went abroad MS Thr 198, folder 85
I know and own my sin MS Eng 611, iii, 36v
I know each lane, and every alley green (incomplete) MS Eng 611, i, 132
I know it: and to know it is despair (incomplete) MS Keats 2.30, 3
I know not but good fortune blind may be MS Eng 635F, 2
I know not what to think. Think no more, let the gods play their game out (incomplete) MS Eng 611, iii, 15v
I know, sir, Both when and what to do without directions (incomplete) MS Eng 265.6, v. 2
I know that envy is too base a guest (incomplete) MS Eng 612, iii, 56
I know you'll say my passion's vile and foul (incomplete) MS Eng 612, iii, 138
I know you're mad, that I refuse to go MS Eng 611, i, 13v
I labor mechanic by night and by day MS Am 1177, 4
I laid me down upon a bank MS Eng 1167, 58; MS Eng 1167, 70; MS Eng 889, 48
I languish and pine (incomplete) MS Eng 614, 87
I laud with all my heart the royal cavalier MS Eng 699, 31
I lately saw what now I sing MS Eng 768 (vol. 2), 73v
I laughed to see a lady out of date (incomplete) MS Eng 611, ii, 87v
I lay sick and very sick MS Eng 1471, vii, 65
I leave mortality and things below MS Eng 584, 88
I led my Silvia to a grove MS Eng 808 (8), 92
I lift my voice up to the Lord MS Eng 639, 19
I like a ship in a storm was lost MS Eng 1038.1, 48v
I, like the fox, shall grieve, whose mate hath left her side MS Eng 1038.1, 50
I, like the shaded nightingale, would sing MS Eng 601.66, 9
I liked but never loved before MS Eng 602F, 12
I little thought that I, O Lord MS Eng 676F, 17v
I lo'e nae a laddie but ane MS Eng 1491 (4), i, 90v
I long to talk with some old lover's ghost MS Eng 966.3, 39; MS Eng 966.1, 34; MS Eng 966.7, 8v; MS Eng 966.5, 135v; MS Eng 966.4, 192v
I look no higher than I can reach (incomplete) MS Eng 611, iii, 4
I look'd around upon the carved sides (incomplete) MS Keats 1.64, 2
I love a lass but cannot show it MS Eng 895, 54v
I love all waste And solitary places; where we taste (incomplete) MS Eng 1274, ch. 111
I love him, I love him, the truth for to say MS Eng 1503 (3), vol. i, p. 49
I love the face where sits MS Eng 626, 6
I love the world, as clients love the laws (incomplete) MS Eng 616, i, 23
Ilove thee for thy fickleness MS Eng 895, 53
I love thee, O my Lord (incomplete) MS Eng 611, iii, 42v
I lov'd thee once, I'll love no more MS Eng 540
I loved in just proportion as I knew (incomplete) MS Am 2349, v, p. 177
I made a posy while the day ran by MS Eng 631, 31
I made of my friend my foe (incomplete) MS Eng 1482, Harl 116, 170v
I madly loved and doted blindly MS Eng 569.68, 5
I marched three miles through scorching sand MS Eng 629, 128v
I married my wife in the light o' the moon MS Eng 1497, ii, 147v
I married to a scolding wife (incomplete) MS Eng 1470, 73
I may forget to eat, to drink, to sleep MS Eng 966.1, 46; MS Eng 966.7, 94v
I may, I must, I can, I will, I do MS Eng 265.6, v. 2
I met of late upon a horse astride MS Eng 699, 25
I might have lived a noble life MS Am 2349, ii, p. 232
I might have lived merrily if I had sinned never MS Eng 1503 (3), vol. i, p. 42
I mind and I will, the will that I may MS Eng 1015, 122v
I mock thee not, tho' I be thee am mocked MS Eng 1167, 14; MS Eng 889, 7
I muse the mystery was not made a science (incomplete) MS Eng 265.6, v. 2
I muse what sickness struck him dead MS Eng 686, 18
I must be of the worldbut let me be MS Keats 3.13, i, 26
I need no muse to give my passion vent MS Eng 631, 92
I need no trophies to adorn my hearse MS Eng 686, 85; MS Eng 686, 102
I ne'er did derogate in all my life (incomplete) MS Eng 611, iii, 32
I never knew foundations laid in blood (incomplete) MS Eng 611, iii, 28
I never preferred to hang in my garters (incomplete) MS Eng 612, ii, 60
I never speak but in my sleep MS Eng 1323, 11
I never speak nothing but truth MS Am 1177, 12
I never stooped so low as they MS Eng 966.3, 70v; MS Eng 966.7, 7; MS Eng 966.5, 137
I never yet in Hippocrene did lap MS Eng 899, 5
I now think love is rather deaf than blind MS Eng 626, 79
I often for my king have stood MS Eng 629, 24
I often wish'd I had a farm MS Eng 616, i, 25
I once despairedfor fortune chilled MS Keats 3.13, ii, 11v
I only remember that our Lord has taught (incomplete) MS Eng 612, iii, 78v
I own, my friend, that to the poor MS Keats 3.13, i, 53v
I own my shape is somewhat odd MS Eng 676F, 20
I pass all my days with a lusty yound whore MS Eng 636F, 143v
I pass their warlike pomp, their proud array (incomplete) MS Eng 616, i, 1
I passed to a very fine room, thro' a porch (incomplete) MS Eng 611, ii, 85
I pity, from my soul, unhappy men (incomplete) MS Eng 611, ii, 61
I pray thee, sweet, to me be kind MS Eng 626, 8
I prithee no more dear importunate wife MS Eng 569.65, 20
I rade to London yesterday MS Eng 1471, vii, 172
I reach all things near me and far off to boot MS Eng 768 (vol. 1), 46v
I rede you yelde up your bond (incomplete) MS Eng 1470, 216
I remember that a smile MS Eng 703, 65v
I rose up at the dawn of day MS Eng 1167, 45; MS Eng 1167, 75; MS Eng 889, 38
I, Rubens, am a statesman and a saint MS Eng 1167, 20; MS Eng 889, 13
I sae bonny, I sae reed (incomplete) MS Eng 1444, 28
I said to my bard with his ribband so blue MS Eng 629, 19v
I said to me heart between sleeping and waking MS Eng 629, 19
I sailed in a tight little schooner MS Thr 198, folder 69
I saw chapel all of gold MS Eng 1167, 58; MS Eng 1167, 71; MS Eng 889, 48
I saw a flow'r whose crimson leaves MS Am 567, 14v
I saw a fury whetting a death dart (incomplete) MS Eng 1274, ch. 86
I saw a monk of Charlemaine MS Eng 1167, 7
I saw a peacock with a fiery tail MS Keats 3.13, i, 30v
I saw a young and beauteous maid MS Am 988, 21v
I saw dark clouds in your fierce lover's eyes (incomplete) MS Eng 611, iii, 24v
I saw 'em kindle with desire MS Eng 1167, 45; MS Eng 889, 38
I saw fair Cloris walk alone MS Eng 686, 60v
I saw my love a sailing, down by a river side MS Am 2349, xxiv, 388
I saw the lass whom dear I loved MS Eng 895, 47
I saw the man in the moon MS Eng 1471, i, 142v
I saw the new moon late yestreen (incomplete) MS Eng 1471, vi, 13
I saw the rain the water rade MS Eng 1497, ii, 120
I saw the snail draw the whale MS Eng 1470, 49
I saw two Beings in the hues of youth MS Eng 630, 26
I say I will so heed my ways if I sin not with tongue MS Eng 639, 14v
I say you platly, so as it seemeth me (incomplete) MS Eng 1482, Harl 2255, 88
I scarce believe my love to be so pure MS Eng 966.3, 68v; MS Eng 966.1, 38; MS Eng 966.5, 139v; MS Eng 966.4, 194
I scarce believed my love to be so pure MS Eng 966.7, 39
I scarcely understand my own intent (incomplete) MS Eng 265.6, v. 2 (twice)
I' scarlet town where I was born MS Eng 1497, i, 163v
I scorn the blaze of courts, the pomp of kings MS Eng 612, ii, 99v
"I see and hold my peace," a princely posey right MS Typ 14, 44
"I see, I see," the mother said MS Eng 1167, 66
I see no cause but men may pick their teeth (incomplete) MS Eng 265.6, v. 2 (twice)
I see well what was meant MS Eng 639, 20
I seek not at once in a female to find MS Eng 895, 16
I seem'd to hear Sounds gathering upwards, accents incomplete (incomplete) MS Eng 1274, ch. 44
I seen a silly sight the last night MS Eng 862, 145
I shall not spare when I sever a praise MS Eng 645, 15v
I should have told You, sir, I have discovered the Moor to be a rascal (incomplete) MS Eng 611, iii, 16v
I, silly cross, that here do stand MS Eng 1503 (3), vol. iii, p. 56v"; MS Eng 749, 125
I sing an old proverb that's very well known MS Eng 629, 65
I sing no harm, good sooth, to any wight MS Eng 966.5, 74v; MS Eng 966.4, 182
I sing not of battles that now are to cease MS Eng 895, 8v
I sing of a meeting has happened of late MS Eng 629, 4v
I sing of a tutor renowned MS Eng 569.63, 13
I sing of deadly dolorous debate MS Eng 266, 69
I sing the day, bright with peculiar charms MS Am 573.2, 2
I sing the man in whose dire looks appear MS Am 1369, 6v
I sing the name which none can say MS Eng 631, 58
I sing the praise of a worthy wight MS Eng 636F, 123
I sing the praise of heroes brave MS Eng 629, 61v
I sing the progress of a deathless soul MS Eng 966.3, 86; MS Eng 966.5, 50
I sing the theme of Milton's muse disdained (incomplete) MS Eng 569.68, 3v
I slept in the dark MS Eng 1167, 55; MS Eng 889, 47
I speak softly, because I will not hear myself (incomplete) MS Eng 265.6, v. 2
I spent my time in rioting MS Am 2349, xxi, 63